Guide to the John McComb Architectural Drawings Collection 1766-1829 PR 40
New-York Historical Society
- Elevation, unidentified (Box McComb Box 5, Item 85)
- Elevation, unidentified (Box McComb Box 17, Item 339 (1))
- Elevation, unidentified (Box McComb Box 14, Item 246)
- Engraving "FLORE": LC (Box McComb Box 22, Item 4)
- Engraving "In the Collection of Dr. Mead": LL-LC (Box McComb Box 22, Item 005b)
- Engraving "LE POEME PASTORAL.": LL-LR (Box McComb Box 22, Item 004b)
- Engraving "Bacchus.": LC (Box McComb Box 22, Item 004a)
- Engraving "Monument of Hevelius at Dantzick.": LL-LR (Box McComb Box 22, Item 3)
- Engraving "A CAR. DE FARNESIO SRE VICEC.": UL-UR (Box McComb Box 22, Item 6)
- Engraving Female Figure as Church of England: attrib. (Box McComb Box 22, Item 4)
- Engraving Crowning of Seated Man with Putti: attrib. (Box McComb Box 22, Item 458)
- Engraving "L'HYVER": LC (Box McComb Box 22, Item 004c)
- Engraving Tools to Move Stone: attrib. (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 479)
- Engraving "Avanzi del Tempio del Dio Canopo nella Villa Adriana in Tivoli": LC (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 467)
- Engraving "Veduta dell' Arco di Tito": LC (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 483)
- Engraving "Veduta della fonte e delle Spelonche d' Egeria fuor della porta Capena or di S. Seb.no": LR (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 489)
- Engraving Architectural Details: attrib. (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 477)
- Engraving "Tempio antico volgarmente detto della Salute": LC-LR (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 488)
- Engraving "Veduta dell' interno dell' Amfiteatro Flavio detto il Colosseo": LL-LC (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 487)
- Engraving Antique Marble Vase and Pedestal: attrib. (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 480)
- Engraving "Vue de la Place de Banchi": LL (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 465)
- Engraving "Veduta di una parte de' fondamenti del Teatro di Marcello": LL-LR (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 471)
- Engraving "PROSPECTVS MONTIS VENTORVM, QVI DICITVR CAROLINVS PROPE VRBEM CASSEL AQVARVM DECIDENTIVM LVSIBVS, FONTIVM, ARBORVM, AC STATVARVM DISPOSITIONE (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 462)
- Engraving 2 Antique Vases: attrib. (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 482)
- Engraving "Frammenti della Camera sepolcrale dirimpetto alla Chiesa di S. Sebast.o fuori delle mura": LL-LR (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 476)
- Engraving Architectural Details from various Villas and Palazzos: attrib. (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 478)
- Engraving Interior View of the Temple of Neptune: attrib. (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 466)
- Engraving "DIVO - ANTONINO - AVG - PIO ANTONINVS - AVGVSTVS - ET VERVS - AVGVSTVS - FILII": UC (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 481)
- Engraving "Vue de la Englise de Carignano": LL (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 464)
- Engraving "Veduta del Tempio ottangolare di Minerva Medica": LL-LC (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 468)
- Engraving "Avanzi del Tempio detto di Apollo nella Villa Adriana vicini a Tivoli": LR (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 492)
- Engraving "Avanzi della Villa di Mecenate a Tivoli, costruita di travertini a opera incerta": LL (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 490)
- Engraving "Al Signore Egidio Earle Cavaliere Inglese amtore delle belle arti": UL-UR (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 469)
- Engraving "Veduta sul Monte Quirinale del Palazzo dell' Eccellentissima Casa Barberini, Architettura del Cav.r Bernino": LL-LR (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 493)
- Engraving "Veduta del Tempio, detto della Tosse": LC-LR (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 486)
- Engraving "Sepolcro di Cecilia Metella": LL-LC (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 484)
- Engraving "VEDUTA in-terna della Chiesa della Madonna degli Angioli detta della Certosa, che anticam.e era la principal Sala delle Terme di Diocleziano. (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 495)
- Engraving "Modo col quale furono alzati grossi Travertini, e gli altri Marmi nel fabbricare il gran Sepolcro di Cecilia Metella, oggi detto capo di Bove (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 475)
- Engraving "Veduta in prospettiva dell' altro Candelabro antico che si vede nel Museo del Cavalier Piranesi": UL-UR (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 472)
- Engraving "Veduta della Villa dell' Emo Sig.r Card Alesandro Albani fuori di Porta Salaria": LR (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 496)
- Engraving "Altra Veduta del tempio della Sibilla in Tivoli": LL (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 485)
- Engraving "Rovine delle Terme Antoniniane": LC (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 491)
- Engraving Antique Marble Vase: attrib. (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 470)
- Engraving Stone details: attrib. (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 474)
- Engraving "Vue du Palais de Monsieur Marcello Durazzo dans la rue Balbi": LL (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 463)
- Engraving "Veduta del Ponte Molle sul Tevere due miglia lontan da Roma": LC-LR (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 494)
- Engraving Trevi Fountain: attrib. (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 473)
- Engraving "Avanzi di una Sala appar-tenente al Castro Pretorio nel-la Villa Adriana in Tivoli.": LC (Box McComb: Oversize, Item 497)
- Engraving/Print "CHRIST CROWNED WITH THORNS": LL-LR (Box McComb Box 22, Item 459)
- Engravings (Box McComb Box 22, Item 2)
- Engravings "Kriegs Trophen.": LC (Box McComb Box 22, Item 002b)
- Engravings Chinoiserie: attrib. (Box McComb Box 22, Item 002c)
- Engravings "Kriegs Trophen.": LC (Box McComb Box 22, Item 002e)
- Engravings "No. 20.": LC (Box McComb Box 22, Item 2)
- Engravings "Kriegs Trophen, Chez Fietta et Comp d' Kriegshaber pres d'Augsburg.": ink, LL-LR (Box McComb Box 22, Item 002a)
- Engravings "Krigs Trophen.": ink, LC (Box McComb Box 22, Item 2)
- Engravings "No. 20.": LC (Box McComb Box 22, Item 002g)
- Engravings, 6 bound together Fireplace and Mantelpiece: attrib. (Box McComb Box 22, Item 001c)
- Engravings, 6 bound together Fireplace and Mantelpiece: attrib. (Box McComb Box 22, Item 001b)
- Engravings, 6 bound together Fireplace and Mantelpiece: attrib. (Box McComb Box 22, Item 001e)
- Engravings, 6 bound together Fireplace and Mantelpiece: attrib. (Box McComb Box 22, Item 001a)
- Engravings, 6 bound together "Nouveaux desseins de Cheminees a peu de Frais": MC-LC (Box McComb Box 22, Item 1)
- Engravings, 6 bound together Fireplace and Mantelpiece (2 images): attrib. (Box McComb Box 22, Item 1)
- Entablature profile Profiles of entablatures: attributed (Box McComb Box 19, Item 377 verso)
- Equestrian Amphitheatre ink, MC: "Horse Path" (Box McComb Box 21, Item 453)
- Erie Canal ink, LC: "Sectio thro' middle" (Box McComb Box 21, Item 455)
- Erie Canal ink, UL-UR: "ROADWAY CULVERT ON SECTION 318." (Box McComb Box 21, Item 454)
- Etons Neck Lighthouse Ink, LC: "Plan, Elevation & Section of the different Buildings intended to be Erected at Etons Neck on Long Island New York", 1798, August 4 ink LC (Box McComb Box 5, Item 82)
- Exterior Partial Elevation Sketch, attrib. One bay 1 3/4 stories with Gibbsian reveals: attrib. (Box McComb Box 20, Item 424)
- Female sketch (Box McComb Box 20, Item 425 verso)
- Firehouse (Box McComb Box 15, Item 265)
- Fireplaces Three fireplaces, six designs: attributed (Box McComb Box 19, Item 377)
- Floor, manner of lowering Manner of lowering a floor without breaking it up. Ink ML to MR (Box McComb box 2, Item 037a recto)
- Fort at Dunkirk [Chautauqua, NY] Pencil, LC: "Plan of a Fort at Dunkirk" Pile, Rack for Hoisting a gate, [1794] (Box McComb Box 5, Item 81)
- Fort Diamond, 1817 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 160a recto)
- Fort Diamond ink, UC-UL: "drawings done for Fort diamond when the contract was made for the Stone-", 1817 (Box McComb Box 10, Item 160b verso)
- Fort William, attrib. (Box McComb Box 10, Item 161)
- Fort, unidentified (Box McComb Box 9, Item 159b verso)
- Fort, unidentified (Box McComb Box 9, Item 157)
- Fort, unidentified (Box McComb Box 9, Item 156)
- Fort, unidentified (Box McComb Box 9, Item 158a recto)
- Fort, unidentified (Box McComb Box 10, Item 162)
- Fort, unidentified (Box McComb Box 9, Item 159a recto)
- Fort, unidentified (Box McComb Box 10, Item 163)
- Fort, unidentified (Box McComb Box 9, Item 158b verso)
- Fort, unidentified (Box McComb Box 9, Item 154)
- Fortification, plan for defense of slope [attrib.] ink, ML-MR: "Profile of the Body of the Place & the Revelin with Revetement" (Box McComb box 6, Item 102b verso)
- Fragment of a shield, axe, spear, points of picks and an oak leaf, attrib. (Box McComb Box 16, Item 308 verso)
- Framing of a roof and top of cupola, attrib. (Box McComb Box 20, Item 422)
- Framing of a roof, attrib. (Box McComb Box 20, Item 421)
- Framing of a roof, attributed ink, UR: "Top of Arch" (Box McComb Box 20, Item 420)
- Francis Childs House pencil, LL-LR: "Design'd for Mr Francis Childs" (Box McComb Box 14, Item 240)
- French's idea for a steam pump An Idea for a steam pump by W (Mr.?) French. Ink UC - UR (Box McComb box 2, Item 36)
- Front stoop Front stoop (Box McComb box 1, Item 022b)
- Furnace (Box McComb Box 5, Item 90)
- G. Gilfert Seal, attrib. (Box McComb Box 22, Item 005a)
- Garden Folly, attributed (Box McComb Box 18, Item 350)
- Gasner Property Plan Plan of Property belonging to the Heirs of Mr. John Gasner sold at auction Jany. Ink UL to UR (Box McComb box 2, Item 037b verso)
- Gate, attrib. (Box McComb Box 9, Item 147)
- Geometric figures (Box McComb box 2, Item 032a recto)
- Geometric figures (Box McComb box 2, Item 032b verso)
- Gothic study, attrib. Gothic tracery with lozenge in center: attrib. (Box McComb Box 16, Item 304)
- Government House Main floor plan (attrib.), [1790] (Box McComb box 3, Item 55)
- Government House North Elevation, Government House (attrib.), [1790] (Box McComb box 3, Item 56)
- Government House Main floor plan (attrib.), [1790] (Box McComb box 3, Item 57)
- Government House Main floor plan [attrib], 1790-1791 (Box McComb box 3, Item 058a recto)
- Government House, executed plan Main floor plan (attrib.), [1790] (Box McComb box 3, Item 54)
- Government Mansion, attributed, 1790 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 395)
- Hoisting machine sketch, attrib. ink, UC-UR: "Hoisting machine taken from 13. Vol. of Repistory of the Arts Page 300" (Box McComb Box 16, Item 309)
- Hospital, unidentified (Box McComb Box 15, Item 266a recto)
- House and store plan, attributed (Box McComb Box 20, Item 411)
- House for a cotton manufactury House For a Cotton Manufactury (Box McComb box 1, Item 025b verso)
- House, unidentified Dutch door with 2 panels below and 4 above: attributed, 1797 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 382)
- House, unidentified (Box McComb Box 20, Item 411 verso)
- House, unidentified Front Elevation: attributed (Box McComb Box 19, Item 409)
- House, unidentified (Box McComb Box 20, Item 410)
- Houses - various plans, unidentified ink, LL-LC: "Two Plans for Single Houses of 45'- by 28'- 0"-" (Box McComb Box 19, Item 408)
- Hudson River to Lake Erie table of water levels Scale of Levels between Lake Erie and Hudson River. Ink, UL (Box McComb box 2, Item 30)
- ink, UC-UR: "Supreme court door Rear Steps- The Roof" ink, UR: "The Recorders grate to be contra( )"... (Box McComb Box 18, Item 353 verso)
- Insane asylum Plan of first floor for insane asylum: attributed (Box McComb Box 12, Item 214)
- Kiln, [1794] (Box McComb Box 5, Item 80)
- King, Rufus House Ink, LL-LR: "Two different Pitches of Roofs designed for Rufus King Esq. House" (Box McComb Box 5, Item 099a)
- King, Rufus House ink, LL-LR: "Elivation of a House design'd for Rufus King Esquire" (Box McComb Box 14, Item 241)
- King, Rufus House, elevation NA (Box McComb Box 5, Item 099b)
- King, Rufus House, plans - pencil LR and pencil verso Plans of basement Story, Principal Floor, Bedchamber Floor [attrib.] (Box McComb Box 5, Item 98)
- Last Pan Last Pan (Box McComb box 1, Item 022c)
- LeRoy, Bayards & Co stores ink, UL: "No S. First Class Hazards" (Box McComb Box 15, Item 255)
- Library, unidentified (Box McComb box 4, Item 72)
- Lighthouse Ink, LC: "Top View of the Lamp when Complete" (Box McComb Box 5, Item 84)
- Lighthouse (Box McComb Box 5, Item 83)
- Lighthouse at Cape Henry (Box McComb Box 5, Item 75)
- Lighthouse at Cape Henry (Drawer case 38 drawer 6, Item 77)
- Lighthouse at Eaton's Neck, L.I.N.Y. (Box McComb box 4, Item 78)
- London asylum, Guys Hospital. West Riding asylum Plan of the London Afsylum for the care & cure of the Insane by Jas. Bevans architect 1814. Ink LL. Lunatic House at Guys Hospital. Ink UR. On (Box McComb box 2, Item 27)
- Lunatic asylum ink wash, LL-LR: "ELEVATIONS OF LUNATIC ASYLUM" (Box McComb Box 15, Item 268)
- Lunatic asylum "ASYLUM": MC, 1808; July 15 (Box McComb Box 22)
- Lunatic hospital ink, LL-LR: "Plan Showing how the Lunatic Hospital can be altered to make good accomodations for a Marine Hospital", 1826 (Box McComb Box 12, Item 213)
- Manhattan Water Works reservoir, [1799] wm. 1797 (Box McComb Box 19, Item 399)
- Map of Brooklyn waterfront & Governors Island (Box McComb Box 21, Item 436)
- Map of lots along river block, attributed (Box McComb Box 17, Item 347)
- Map of New York Harbor Ink, LR: "A Plan of the Harbour of New York from an Actual Survey made by Dirictions of the Corporation of a Millitary com. by Capt. J Chaunce, [1798] (Drawer case 38 drawer 6, Item 87)
- Mathematical calculations for a pump (Box McComb box 1, Item 007 verso)
- McComb Property alteration ink, MR: "Plan for improving the property of Jno. McComb corner of Broadway & Amity Lane" (Box McComb Box 12, Item 215)
- McComb Property alteration ink, LL-LR: "Sketch showing how the Lots on corner of Broad way and Amity Lane can be improved by being divided into Six Lots", 1827; May (Box McComb Box 12, Item 216)
- McComb, plan of lots, truss of [Bleecker St. Church], 1825 (Box McComb Box 11, Item 190b verso)
- McComb's Lots, Caroline Street ink, LC: "Plan for improving Jn.o McComb's Lot-" (Box McComb Box 17, Item 343)
- McComb's Projects, attrib. "Buildings designed by Jn.o McComb with the exception of the Steeple of St. Johns Church": ink, LL-LR, with border (Box McComb Box 22, Item 338)
- Mechanical, boat Pencil, LL-LC: "Plan & Section of a Boat for Carring Stone H.", [1794] (Box McComb box 4, Item 79)
- Mechanical, unidentified (Box McComb box 2, Item 35)
- Monuments, 3, Church, unidentified (Box McComb box 4, Item 067b)
- Moore, Rev. Benjamin house ink, LL-LC: "Basement Story", 1794; or [1802] (Box McComb Box 19, Item 406)
- Moore, Rev. Benjamin house ink, LL-LR: "Plan of a House design'd for Rev-d Benjamin Moore at Greenwich-", 1794(?);orighouse 1802c. (Box McComb Box 19, Item 405)
- Mouldings and decorative details Foliage designs between circles (Box McComb Box 17, Item 330)
- Murray St. Church ink, MR: "Capital & Base for Gallery Column full Size", 1811 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 144)
- Murray St. Church Ink, LL-LR: "Ground Plan of Murray Street Church", 1811 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 133)
- Murray St. Church ink, MR: "Mouldings for the church in Murray Street-", 1811 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 145)
- Murray St. Church S.s., graphite, LL-LR: [Murray St. Presbyterian or St. John's Chapel?], 1811 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 137)
- Murray St. Church S.s., graphite, LL-LC: [St. John's Chapel or Murray St. Presbyterian?], 1811 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 138)
- Murray St. Church, 1811 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 134)
- Murray St. Church, 1811 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 139)
- Murray St. Church graphite, LC: "Murray Street Church", 1811 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 135)
- Murray St. Church, 1811 (Box McComb Box 8, Item 136)
- Murray St. Church Ink, LL-LC: "Half Cap for Ionic Pilasters for Murray St. Church", 1811 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 140)
- Murray St. Church, attrib. Molding profile: attrib. (Box McComb Box 16, Item 321)
- New York Battery Ink, MR: "Plan Elevations & Sections a Furnace for Heating Ba[llshot] as Executed on the N. York Battery By John MComb" (Box McComb Box 5, Item 91)
- New York Hospital "A Front view of the New York Hospital, -": LL-LR, 1776 (Box McComb Box 22)
- Nicomedes Instrument ink, UC-UR: "Nicomedes Instrument for diminishing columns" (Box McComb Box 20, Item 427)
- Nilo Statue pencil, LL-LR: "Nilo Statua di marmo bigio gia nel Cortile delle Statue in Vaticano" (Box McComb Box 16, Item 303)
- North Dutch Church ink, LL-LR: "Front Elevation of the North dutch Church by John McComb", 1769 (Box McComb Box 13, Item 220)
- North Dutch Church ink, ML-MR: "Plan & Side Elevation of North dutch Church by John Mc.Comb 1772, 1769" (Box McComb Box 13, Item 219)
- Old Presbyterian Church Ink, LC-LR: "Framing of the Roof of the Old Presbyterian Church" (Box McComb Box 10, Item 167 verso)
- Ornamental detail sketch [band of ornament, gothicized palmettes of later Eastlake designs] (Box McComb Box 16, Item 326)
- Painshill garden pump A Section of a New Engine in Painshill Garden for Supplying a Lake which work'd by one horse only in one hour raises to the height of 12 feet, 1771, Feb (Box McComb box 1, Item 7)
- [Palladian villa] plan of country house and grounds, unidentified (Box McComb Box 14, Item 244)
- Panopticon Panopticon Plan for a Prison for Juvenile offenders. Ink UR (Box McComb box 2, Item 26)
- Park Theatre, attributed ink, UC: "Plan of Theater", [1795-1798] (Box McComb Box 13, Item 224)
- Pavilion Elevation (Box McComb Box 8, Item 124)
- Perspective studies Three perspective studies; two landscapes, 1 geometric volumes (Box McComb box 2, Item 33)
- Pilaster, study "Detailed study for cap & fluting of pilaster": attributed (Box McComb Box 19, Item 392 verso)
- Pissoir ink, LR: "Design for a Pissoir" (Box McComb Box 20, Item 414)
- Plan (concentric), unidentified, 1818 (Box McComb Box 16, Item 319)
- Plan, unidentified (Box McComb Box 17, Item 330 verso)
- Plan, unidentified (Box McComb Box 10, Item 174 verso)
- Plan, unidentified (Box McComb Box 10, Item 174 verso)
- Plans - rectangular, unidentified (Box McComb Box 21, Item 452)
- Potters Field Lodge, attributed Ink, UC-UR: "Plan & Elevation of the Lodge at the arsenal the Potters Field August 16, 1808 Jas. Williams [field Engineer?]", 1808; August 16 (Box McComb Box 9, Item 148)
- Potters Field Powder House, attributed Ink, LC: "Plan of the Powder House at Potters Field" (Box McComb Box 9, Item 149)
- Princeton Theological Seminary ink, LC-LR: "Plan designed for the Theological Seminary at Princeton" (Box McComb box 6, Item 115)
- Public Building, unidentified, [1820] (Box McComb Box 13, Item 227)
- Public Building, unidentified, 1820; June 6 (Box McComb Box 13, Item 226)
- Public Building, unidentified ink, LC: "Park - Fronts", 1820; June 10 (Box McComb Box 13, Item 228)
- Public building, unidentified [attrib] elevation (Box McComb box 1, Item 16)
- Pulpit, [1802] (Box McComb Box 16, Item 317)
- Pulpit, unidentified church (Box McComb box 3, Item 059a recto)
- Real Estate Lot Map (Box McComb Box 21, Item 437)
- Real Estate Map - Farm, 1812; Aug. 12 (Box McComb Box 21, Item 439)
- Reservoir Ink, LC: "Elevation of the Reservoir", July 23, 1800 ink, LL (Box McComb Box 5, Item 94)
- Reservoir, 1794, c. (Box McComb Box 5, Item 89)
- Reservoir Ink, ML-MR: "Elevation of a Reservoir of 100.000 Gallons-" (Box McComb Box 5, Item 95)
- Reservoir to contain one million gallons Ink, UL-UR: "Three Sections of different designs for a Reservoir to contain One Million of Gallons" (Box McComb Box 5, Item 88)
- [Residences - conceptual] (Box McComb Box 15, Item 257)
- Residence - 2 family, unidentified Town house: attributed (Box McComb Box 15, Item 250)
- Residence - circular, unidentified ink, LC: "30' Diam.r" (Box McComb Box 15, Item 254)
- Residence - Queen St., unidentified ink, LC: "Queen Street" (Box McComb Box 14, Item 249a recto)
- Residence semi-detached, unidentified (Box McComb Box 14, Item 248)
- Residence semi-detached, unidentified (Box McComb Box 14, Item 247)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb box 1, Item 017b)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb box 6, Item 105)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb Box 5, Item 96)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb box 6, Item 106)
- Residence, unidentified ink, LR: "Elevation drawn by Mr John MComb Senr" (Box McComb Box 13, Item 221)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb box 6, Item 110a recto)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb Box 15, Item 256)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb box 6, Item 108)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb Box 14, Item 243)
- Residence, unidentified ink, LC: "Front" (Box McComb Box 15, Item 251)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb Box 14, Item 242)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb Box 14, Item 249b verso)
- Residence, unidentified [First floor plan] (Box McComb Box 15, Item 259)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb box 6, Item 107)
- Residence, unidentified ink, MC: "Basement Story" (Box McComb Box 15, Item 253)
- Residence, unidentified pencil, LC: "50'. Front." (Box McComb Box 14, Item 235)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb Box 14, Item 245)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb box 6, Item 110b verso)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb box 6, Item 109)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb box 1, Item 12)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb Box 15, Item 260 recto)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb Box 15, Item 258)
- Residence, unidentified ink, LC: "Bed Chamber Floor" (Box McComb Box 15, Item 252)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb box 6, Item 103b verso)
- Residence, unidentified (Box McComb box 6, Item 104)
- Residence, unidentified (vaults of) Coles House? (Box McComb box 6, Item 103a recto)
- Residence, unidentified [attrib] Main floor plan (attrib) (Box McComb box 1, Item 19)
- Residence, unidentified [attrib] (Box McComb box 1, Item 017a)
- Residence, unidentified [attrib] Upper floor plan [attrib] (Box McComb box 1, Item 20)
- Residence, unidentified [attrib] Facade [attrib] (Box McComb box 1, Item 21)
- Residence, unidentified, 2 versions of façade (Box McComb box 4, Item 071b verso)
- Residence, unidentified, semi-detached (Box McComb box 1, Item 13)
- Rotunda plan, attributed (Box McComb Box 17, Item 349)
- Roxalana Roxalana. graphite LC (Box McComb box 2, Item 39)
- School (Box McComb Box 15, Item 269)
- School (Box McComb Box 15, Item 269b recto)
- Schuylkill River Bridge Frame of the Bridge over the River Schuylkill at Philadelphia (Box McComb box 1, Item 9)
- Sessions House A View of the Sessions House for the County of Middlesex on Clerkenwall Green, 1782, Nov 1 (Box McComb box 1, Item 010a)
- Sewer (Box McComb Box 12, Item 205a recto)
- Sewer ink, LC: "Section of a Sewer intended to be built wholly of Brick-" (Box McComb Box 12, Item 203)
- Sewer, (unidentified) (Box McComb Box 11, Item 199b verso)
- Sewer, attributed (Box McComb Box 12, Item 202)
- Sewing machine, attributed, [1799] (Box McComb Box 19, Item 379 verso)
- Shot Tower with flag, attrib. ink, LR "Sketch showing t" (Box McComb Box 21, Item 434)
- Sketch Design for an urn: attributed (Box McComb Box 18, Item 365)
- Sketch [Eagle head and claw] (Box McComb Box 16, Item 301 recto)
- Sketch Four designs for urns: attributed (Box McComb Box 18, Item 363)
- Sketch [Sketch of John Mc.Comb Jr. (cf. Waldo portrait)] (Box McComb Box 16, Item 301 verso)
- Sketch Two light brackets (for gas lights?): attributed (Box McComb Box 18, Item 351)
- Sketch Design on enthemion, scroll and flowers: attributed (Box McComb Box 18, Item 355)
- Sketch Design for Door frame: attributed (Box McComb Box 18, Item 367)
- Sketch Designs for eight urns and one metal grille: attributed (Box McComb Box 18, Item 359)
- Sketch Swags and a head: attributed (Box McComb Box 18, Item 358)
- Sketch [swags of grapes with ribbons] (Box McComb Box 16, Item 327)
- Sketch A design for cornices of doors: attrib. (Box McComb Box 16, Item 324 verso)
- Sketch Stove in a niche: attributed (Box McComb Box 18, Item 362)
- Sketch Two designs for mantels: attributed (Box McComb Box 18, Item 360)
- Sketch Three designs for urns: attributed (Box McComb Box 18, Item 364)
- Sketch Steps and railing and three designs for metal work: attributed (Box McComb Box 18, Item 361)
- Sketch Circular doodles: attrib. (Box McComb Box 15, Item 260 verso)
- Sketch Scroll design: attrib. (Box McComb Box 18, Item 356)